Seema P Pateela

#G001, SIRI MANE, 7th Cross, Soumya Clusters, Garden Villas, Nagarbhavi - 560072

OBJECTIVE

To build my career in Investment Banking by associating myself with a progressive organization, where there is ample scope for individual development, apply my skill to the organization, to provide quality services to the field of Investment Banking and to acquire experience in working with a good organization.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Cambridge Institute of Technology, Banalore

Master's in Business Administration in Finance 2008-2010

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- · Demonstrated analytical and writing skills, effective communication skills, and a high level of attention to detail
- An opportunity to demonstrate strong leadership and coaching skills, developing future leaders within the team
- Excellent communication skills and ability to establish and maintain strong working relationships while working independently in a high-pressured environment
- · Have high attention to detail, excellent time management skills, the ability to work under pressure and working to tight deadlines
- Certified in ix Sigma Yellow Belt, Green Belt & Black Belt
- An advance Excel Knowledge

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOCIETE GENERALE Mar2020–Present

Responsibilities in Société Générale -

Team Lead - Middle Office Management Services

TASKS PERFORMED

- Responsibilities in Middle Office services Mandatory Corporate action department
- Analyzing information received from several sources (Swifts, Bloomberg, DTC) regarding upcoming Corporate Actions (especially Mandatory Corporate Actions). This could include contacting the sources for clarification if unsure of literature/prospectus. Determine proper course of action
- Accurately managing the cash Divided activities, reconciling FO/BO bookings
- Assumes supervisory responsibilities in the absence of the departmental manager, to include escalation situations regarding Corporate Actions
- Reads all correspondence received and determines next course of action (i.e.: Mandatory events positions bookings on Buy Sell/SLB/ ELS Products and notifications to clients.)
- Regularly updating of SOP on Process updates
- Scrutinizes loss information in the event of a missed Corporate Action and submits synopsis to Department Manager explaining in detail the situation
- Maintaining and reconciling various general ledgers and suspense account. This includes compiling various information in an excel spreadsheet format and preparing weekly FOCUS and month end reporting
- Acts as a resource and/or escalation point for Reorg Department co-associates. Handles problematic inquiries from the field and makes
 judgment calls regarding corporate actions, pending allocations, transfer items; researching every aspect as it pertains to the situation,
 even if not a usual function of the department
- Plays an active role in collaborative discussions/meetings pertaining to process and service improvements with internal departments, and outside vendors. Is an active participant in internal/external audits
- Accurate and timely book of corporate action transactions executed on investment funds accounts, verify data received from external
 vendors such as swifts, DTC and Playdate requests in respect of their correctness and completeness
- Identifying ineffective areas within process and initiating changes for them proposing improvement solutions
- Cooperate with other teams/divisions within in scope of performed responsibilities

ACCENTURE May2013 – Mar2020

Responsibilities at ACCENTURE

Designation: Subject Matter Expert

TASKS PERFORMED

Voluntary Corporate Action Department -

• Performing deadline activity of all the corporate action events of Fixed Income/Bonds & Equity specially on US market.

- Complete Knowledge on Corporate actions like Event announcement, Event capture in backstreams and processing the Events on time to get the Elections from Counterparts and the Front Office, passing on the liability to the concerned team, instructing on the Tendered positions and also have a complete knowledge on Buy Sell, Loan Borrow Trades.
- Instructing Notifications in SWIFT's like MT565/MT599
- Convey and manage entire event deadlines with clients both external as well as internal
- Reconcile SWIFT MT564/MT566 (notifications) as received from global custodian versus client's positions held at back-office systems.
- Develop and maintain position to reconcile short, long, borrowing plus lending.
- Managing event flow
- Verify event setup to ensure event details are accurately fed in internal system.

Dividend payment and receipt Back Office Services -

- Reconcile SWIFT MT564/MT566 (notifications) as received from global custodian versus client's positions held at back-office systems on lending and borrow positions.
- Develop and maintain position to reconcile short, long, borrowing plus lending.
- Based on the dates able to ascertain who is eligible to receive the dividend.
- Sound knowledge Stock borrow and lending payments

Achievements:

- Received Numero Uno award for learning the corporate action in short span of time without any core competency and exceeded expectation by meeting the target in clearing the month end breaks prior to SLA.
- Received Numero Uno award for meeting SLA when process underwent short of staff and received many appreciations from management.
- Master Blaster award for submitting productive ideas and implementing the same.
- Cracker of the Month contest winner for clearing 290 cash breaks in one day.
- Received many spot awards.

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

May2012 - July2013

Responsibilities in TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

Designation: Process Associate

TASKS PERFORMED

- Update securities and cash settlement instructions in different applications as per STP (Straight through Process) to ensure timely settlement of the trades.
- Investigate and action missing instructions, agent unmatched and instructions rejected by agent task (trades) as per the workflow.
- Source settlement instructions from alert, company web sites and liaise with Middle Office and client for the counter party's settlement instructions.
- Prime broker accounts reconciliation and approve the addition or amendment of the settlement instruction to these accounts.
- Update and review Deutsche Bank London securities settlement instructions in Alert and post Deutsche Bank London mails in Alert.
- Carry out Internal Audits within the Team based on Four-eye principle.
- Prepare and file the documents as per audit requirements.
- Training, documentation which includes capturing the volumes on daily basis, Error reports and root cause analysis.
- MIS Preparation as per the Client requirement and also presenting as per the Management requirement.
- Working on Internationally used application like Omega Alert and SWIFT messaging services.

Designation: Transaction Processing Officer

TASKS PERFORMED

- Work involved updating cost basis from CBUF and from Legacy.
- As per client request updating cost basis and reconcile their Profit/loss portfolio.
- Reconcile of client accounts, which includes updating financial trackers.
- Monthly reporting with reconciled Financial Trackers, including corporate actions like stock merger, cash merger, stock split, Spin off, reorg and conversions Merger Elections, Tender etc.
- Providing client's quarterly and half yearly historical gain/loss reports and gain/loss report on a yearly basis and supporting clients by providing with the details they need etc.
- Researching and investigating the missing cost basis of the securities held by the client and updating the same in his portfolio accordingly,
 which again involves in applying Corporate Actions to the securities and calculate the exact cost basis and report the same in client 's gain
 and loss report.
- Versus Purchase of Stock on daily basis on the OTC.
- Currently working SWISS & Coatracks (cost basis research and updates) on VSP, online with Client interaction.
- Ensure accounts must be done within the SLA and maintain quality.
- Knowledge in on Stock exchange listed companies and Their Historical Actions Record knowledge.
- Giving the data to client regarding the Misbalanced Amount.

Personal Details

Date of Birth -14/07/1987 Marital Status - Married

Languages - English, Kannada, Hindi

Hobbies and Interests - Photography

I confirm that the information provided by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Seema Pateela Place: Bangalore

Date: